<story-context id="bmad/bmm/workflows/4-implementation/story-context/template" v="1.0">
  <metadata>
    <epicId>1</epicId>
    <storyId>2</storyId>
    <title>Analytics schema foundation (Prisma)</title>
    <status>drafted</status>
    <generatedAt>2025-12-13</generatedAt>
    <generator>BMAD Story Context Workflow</generator>
    <sourceStoryPath>docs/stories/1-2-analytics-schema-foundation.md</sourceStoryPath>
  </metadata>

  <story>
    <asA>Leader</asA>
    <iWant>foundational Prisma schema for analytics groups/tags/time-series metrics</iWant>
    <soThat>the system can ingest and analyze data over time without breaking existing Postiz tables</soThat>
    <tasks>
- Confirm data-model approach for MVP content storage (AC: #1)
- Implement minimal Prisma schema changes (AC: #1)
- Add constraints and indexes (AC: #2)
- Apply migration/push safely (AC: #1)
- Tests: Prisma client smoke / integration (AC: #1, #2)
    </tasks>
  </story>

  <acceptanceCriteria>
1) Given the existing Postiz Prisma schema, when adding the minimum analytics-intelligence tables/models, then schema migration/push succeeds and does not break existing tables.
2) And basic indexes exist for querying by organization/integration/date.
  </acceptanceCriteria>

  <artifacts>
    <docs>
- path: docs/epics.md
  title: postiz-app - Epic Breakdown
  section: Story 1.2
  snippet: Story 1.2 requires adding minimal Prisma tables for group/niche, tags, and metrics time-series, ensuring migration/push succeeds and indexes exist.
- path: docs/architecture.md
  title: Architecture
  section: Database / Data Architecture
  snippet: Architecture mandates Prisma model naming conventions and unique constraints for idempotency keys (organizationId, integrationId, externalContentId, date) for metrics time-series.
- path: docs/tech-spec.md
  title: postiz-app — Tech Spec (Facebook Page Analytics)
  section: Data Model (MVP)
  snippet: Tech spec defines candidate MVP models and constraints for tracked integrations, groups/niches, optional AnalyticsContent, and daily metrics with unique idempotency keys.
- path: package.json
  title: Root package.json
  section: scripts
  snippet: Repo provides prisma scripts for generate and db push against the central schema location.
    </docs>

    <code>
- path: libraries/nestjs-libraries/src/database/prisma/schema.prisma
  kind: schema
  symbol: Organization
  lines: 14-45
  reason: Organization is the tenant boundary; new analytics models must be org-scoped using organizationId/orgId patterns.
- path: libraries/nestjs-libraries/src/database/prisma/schema.prisma
  kind: schema
  symbol: Integration
  lines: 308-350
  reason: Integrations already exist and are org-scoped; analytics tables should link to integrationId where relevant.
- path: libraries/nestjs-libraries/src/database/prisma/schema.prisma
  kind: schema
  symbol: Tags
  lines: 47-60
  reason: Existing Tags model indicates current tagging domain; analytics tagging must avoid breaking existing scheduling tags.
- path: libraries/nestjs-libraries/src/database/prisma/schema.prisma
  kind: schema
  symbol: Post
  lines: 387-437
  reason: Existing Post model can inform decision whether to reuse posts vs maintain dedicated analytics content tables.
    </code>

    <dependencies>
- ecosystem: node
  manifest: package.json
  notable:
    - prisma/@prisma/client 6.5.0
    - postgres datasource via DATABASE_URL
    - scripts: prisma-generate, prisma-db-push
    </dependencies>
  </artifacts>

  <constraints>
- Keep schema changes additive; do not modify existing domain tables in a way that breaks Postiz.
- Ensure analytics tables are org-scoped (Organization is tenant boundary) and optionally link to Integration for per-page data. [Source: libraries/nestjs-libraries/src/database/prisma/schema.prisma]
- Prefer idempotency via unique constraints for metrics time-series (org + integration + externalContentId + date). [Source: docs/architecture.md#Database]
  </constraints>

  <interfaces>
- name: Prisma schema
  kind: database schema
  signature: Prisma schema at libraries/nestjs-libraries/src/database/prisma/schema.prisma
  path: libraries/nestjs-libraries/src/database/prisma/schema.prisma
- name: prisma-generate
  kind: script
  signature: pnpm run prisma-generate
  path: package.json
- name: prisma-db-push
  kind: script
  signature: pnpm run prisma-db-push
  path: package.json
  </interfaces>

  <tests>
    <standards>Use Jest (repo test script). For this story, add a minimal smoke/integration test that Prisma client can initialize and perform basic operations against new analytics tables in a controlled test environment.</standards>
    <locations>
- Prisma schema: libraries/nestjs-libraries/src/database/prisma/schema.prisma
- Jest runner: root package.json scripts.test
    </locations>
    <ideas>
- AC1: Prisma generate + db push succeeds with added models (no runtime schema errors).
- AC2: A minimal query against new tables works and indexes/unique constraints prevent duplicates for idempotency keys.
    </ideas>
  </tests>
</story-context>
